Alan Jackson

Cloud Solutions Architect and Software Developer with over 20 years of experience leading teams, designing, and implementing solutions to solve business problems. Experienced with the oil & gas and photography industries. Primarily used the Microsoft .NET ecosystem and Microsoft Azure Cloud.

3607 Concordance Dr Spring, TX 77386 (817) 751-9957 alandjackson@gmail.com

EXPERIENCE

ExxonMobil, Houston, TX — Systems Architect for Upstream Enterprise Architecture

2020 - PRESENT

Consulted with upstream business groups to design and architect solutions to challenging business problems. Built reference implementations to demonstrate usage of new technologies (mostly in Microsoft Azure). Examples include IOT telemetry streaming, securing web apps and apis, modern auth, and application resource/network topologies. Also worked with the cloud service team to implement secure policies.

ExxonMobil, Houston, TX — Systems Architect for Dynamics and Power Platform

2018 - 2020

Note: XTO Energy was purchased by ExxonMobil in 2010 and run as a subsidiary. Operations were moved from Fort Worth to Houston in the summer of 2018.

Designed, architected, and implemented ExxonMobil's first instance of the Microsoft Dynamics / Power Platform and grew the platform to several hundred users and over a dozen instances.

Dynamics Field service was implemented to maintain oil field equipment and surveillance. Power Platform applications were designed and implemented to digitize a variety of field workflows (permits, well reviews, meter installs, etc.). I was responsible for implementing development practices, data models, integration systems, platform administration procedures, licensing, controls, and monitoring. The platform replaced several legacy and paper based workflows, resulting in significant labor and license cost savings.

XTO Energy, Fort Worth, TX — Supervisor Web Development

2014 - 2018

Staffed and managed a team of between 10 and 15 software developers, working on small and medium sized line of business applications. Converted team to use agile ceremonies (scrum / stand up, sprint planning, retrospectives) and processes (release small increments often, people and

SKILLS

Azure Cloud Architecture

Dynamics 365, Power Platform

.NET, .NET Core, C#, MVC, Razor

ADO, CI/CD, DevOps

Javascript, Angular, React

ASP.NET, ASP.NET Core

WinForms, WPF

PowerShell, BASH

SSRS, Power BI

SQL/RDBMS

NoSQL, CosmosDB

Data Integration

Data Modeling

Virtualization

Agile Coach

Full Stack Development

communication over processes). Maintained a portfolio of over 50 applications, mostly written in c# / asp.net with APIs and SQL backends.

XTO Energy, Fort Worth, TX — Senior Programmer Analyst

2009 - 2014

Developed dozens of line of business applications. Most applications were web apps with a Microsoft SQL backend, but other types of applications were API services, desktop applications, and data integration jobs. Applications mostly digitized manual workflows for departments such as HR, Reserves, Land, and Accounting. Most projects were single or 2 team developer projects, so I was responsible for the full stack of development and gathering requirements, development, user testing, deployment, and support.

Was the technical track lead for a 3 million dollar identity management project that involved multiple websites and dozens of data integrations.

PhotoLynx, **Ramona**, **CA** — Lead Software Engineer

2003 - 2008

Head of software development for a small software company that provides software solutions for the independent school photography industry.

Created, maintained, and supported a suite of desktop applications that supported data driven digital workflows for school photography (capture, image adjustment, data entry, image rendering and printing, green screen, etc).

Applications were written in VB6, C++ (COM), C#, WinForms, and WPF. Most applications used an Access or SQL CE back end. Supported legacy applications and created a plug in system to develop new features on old applications.

University of California Riverside, Riverside, CA — Systems Administrator

2000 - 2003

Maintained and developed the IT infrastructure for the UCR computer science department, including public computer labs, research labs, staff and faculty computers, and a server farm providing network services (Web, Mail, DNS, Windows Domains, NAS, etc.).

Developed and deployed/supported a disk based backup system with a restore web front end in PERL. Developed a one step lab installation method for deploying lab computers using Linux Mandrake and virtualized Windows under VMware.

EDUCATION

University of California Riverside, Riverside, CA — B.S. Computer Science and Engineering

1998-2002

3.5 overall GPA

Coursework in simulation, graphics, operating systems, networks, compilers, and algorithms.

Also completed graduate courses in data structures, graphics, and networking along with graduate research in the area of simulating physical properties of water and bubbles.

REFERENCES

Contact info provided upon request.

Jordan Bean — Systems Administrator

https://www.linkedin.com/in/jordan-bean/

John Rowan — Data Architect at ExxonMobil

https://www.linkedin.com/in/john-rowan-43b13bb/

Jim Boud — Senior Azure Data Architect at Cognizant

https://www.linkedin.com/in/jim-boud-0565a91/